<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>idkcode, the blog</title>
    <description>...</description>
    <link>http://idkcode.comhttp://idkcode.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://idkcode.comhttp://idkcode.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 17:53:32 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 17:53:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Post One: An Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-acquainted&quot;&gt;Getting Acquainted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first post, I wanted to introduce myself as a software engineer, and the project on which my team and I will be reporting on for our Software Engineering class for this Fall 2016 Semester. I am a Junior at Drew University majoring in Computer Science and Economics with a deep interest in data analytics. I interned this past summer in Boston with Fidelity Investments’ Quantitative Technology group, and the summer prior to that with Corning Incorporated’s Information Security group. Now, in my Software Engineering class, I will be working with a team of students to leverage our collective knowledge and experience to build a real-world software application for a client from Drew University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-client&quot;&gt;Our Client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our client is a sociology professor at Drew who has spearheaded efforts to provide a directory of services and activities to those new and old in the community of Orange, New Jersey. From arts and festivals, to child services and clinics, our client has collected a vast amount of information from her community in an effort to promote local businesses, and aid newcomers in finding what they need when they need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-challenge&quot;&gt;Our Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our client has enlisted our services to build a rich mobile application that can display the wealth of information in her existing database of business and service providers in Orange to a wide audience. The challenge is not only to create a full-featured, multi-platform application that can deliver this information, but also a low-tech component that intermediaries can use to ‘export’ addresses, contacts, and other information to emails, texts, or other media for users without a smartphone. We are also pushing for a multi-lingual interface as this would dramatically increase the user-base and usefulness of the application in its intended context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-framework&quot;&gt;The Framework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionic.io&quot;&gt;Ionic Framework&lt;/a&gt; in part because it was the framework of choice for our original mapping protocol, Geotagger. While we may be using a different mapping protocol, the Ionic framework is a perfect choice for our use-case as we are able to build a single application that can be deployed on the web, and both major mobile platforms: iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organization&quot;&gt;Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we have managed to split our workload up according to the three major components of the application resulting in a View Team, a Model Team, and a Controller Team, each responsible for engineering that particular component in conjunction with the remaining two teams. The three teams are all present at customer meetings with a spokesperson or business analyst of sorts from each so that their questions and concerns are addressed in customer meetings and amongst team members&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;forward-outlook&quot;&gt;Forward Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have gathered the main requirements from our customer, the View Team of which I am a part hopes to create a mock-interface for the customer to demo and provide feedback. We also hope to begin integrating some of the controller logic into the application depending on the progress of that team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading the first post, and be sure to come back for more over the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 19:21:44 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://idkcode.comhttp://idkcode.com/blog/swe-class/2016/10/09/blog-post-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://idkcode.comhttp://idkcode.com/blog/swe-class/2016/10/09/blog-post-one.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>swe-class</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
